import { useReducer } from "react";
import Header from "./Components/Header";
import Main from "./Main";
import Loader from "./Components/Loader";
import Error from "./Components/Error";
import Question from "./Components/Question";
import NextButton from "./Components/NextButton";
import Progress from "./Components/Progress";
import StartScreen from "./Components/StartScreen";
import FinishedSceen from "./Components/FinishedScreen";
import Timer from "./Components/Timer";
import Footer from "./Components/Footer";
const SEC_PER_QUESTION = 30;

//loading,error,ready,active,finished
const initialState = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
      options: ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "Which company invented React?",
      options: ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "What's the fundamental building block of React apps?",
      options: ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question:
        "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the UI in React components?",
      options: ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "How does data flow naturally in React apps?",
      options: [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "The developers decides",
      ],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "How to pass data into a child component?",
      options: ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parameters"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "When to use derived state?",
      options: [
        "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
        "Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
        "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
        "Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question: "What triggers a UI re-render in React?",
      options: [
        "Running an effect",
        "Passing props",
        "Updating state",
        "Adding event listeners to DOM elements",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question: 'When do we directly "touch" the DOM in React?',
      options: [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the UI",
        "When we need to add styles",
        "Almost never",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question: "In what situation do we use a callback to update state?",
      options: [
        "When updating the state will be slow",
        "When the updated state is very data-intensive",
        "When the state update should happen faster",
        "When the new state depends on the previous state",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "If we pass a function to useState, when will that function be called?",
      options: [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render",
        "The first time we update the state",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render?",
      options: ["useState", "useEffect", "useRef", "useReducer"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array?",
      options: [
        "Usually none",
        "All our state variables",
        "All state and props referenced in the effect",
        "All variables needed for clean up",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question: "An effect will always run on the initial render.",
      options: [
        "True",
        "It depends on the dependency array",
        "False",
        "In depends on the code in the effect",
      ],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "When will an effect run if it doesn't have a dependency array?",
      options: [
        "Only when the component mounts",
        "Only when the component unmounts",
        "The first time the component re-renders",
        "Each time the component is re-rendered",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 20,
    },
  ],
  status: "ready",
  index: 0,
  answer: null,
  points: 0,
  highscore: 0,
  secondsRemaining: null,
};
function reducer(state, action) {
  switch (action.type) {
    case "loading":
      return { ...state, status: "loading" };

    case "dataReceived":
      return { ...state, status: "ready", questions: action.payload };

    case "dataFailed":
      return { ...state, status: "error" };

    case "start":
      return {
        ...state,
        status: "active",
        secondsRemaining: state.questions.length * SEC_PER_QUESTION,
      };

    case "newAnswer":
      const question = state.questions.at(state.index);
      return {
        ...state,
        answer: action.payload,
        points:
          action.payload === question.correctOption
            ? state.points + question.points
            : state.points,
      };

    case "nextQuestion":
      return { ...state, index: state.index + 1, answer: null };

    case "finish":
      return {
        ...state,
        answer: null,
        status: "finished",
        highscore:
          state.points > state.highscore ? state.points : state.highscore,
      };

    case "tick":
      console.log("Tick is called and state is");
      console.log(state);
      return {
        ...state,
        secondsRemaining: state.secondsRemaining - 1,
        status: state.secondsRemaining === 0 ? "finished" : state.status,
      };

    case "restart":
      return {
        ...initialState,
        highscore: state.highscore,
        status: "ready",
        questions: state.questions,
      };

    default:
      throw new Error("Something is wrong in the reducer");
  }
}
function App() {
  const [state, dispatch] = useReducer(reducer, initialState);
  const {
    questions,
    status,
    index,
    answer,
    points,
    highscore,
    secondsRemaining,
  } = state;
  console.log(secondsRemaining);
  const maxPossiblePoints = questions.reduce(
    (acc, curr) => acc + curr.points,
    0
  );
  let numQuestions = questions.length;
  // useEffect(function () {
  //   fetch(`http://localhost:8000/questions`)
  //     .then((res) => res.json())
  //     .then((data) => {
  //       dispatch({ type: "dataReceived", payload: data });
  //     })
  //     .catch((err) => {
  //       console.log(err);
  //       dispatch({ type: "dataFailed" });
  //     });
  // }, []);

  return (
    <div className="app">
      <Header />
      <Main>
        {status === "loading" && <Loader />}
        {status === "error" && <Error />}
        {status === "ready" && (
          <StartScreen numQuestions={numQuestions} dispatch={dispatch} />
        )}
        {status === "active" && (
          <>
            <Progress
              numQuestions={numQuestions}
              index={index}
              points={points}
              maxPossiblePoints={maxPossiblePoints}
              answer={answer}
            />
            <Question
              question={questions[index]}
              dispatch={dispatch}
              answer={answer}
            />
            <Footer>
              <Timer dispatch={dispatch} secondsRemaining={secondsRemaining} />
              <NextButton
                dispatch={dispatch}
                answer={answer}
                numQuestions={numQuestions}
                index={index}
              />
            </Footer>
          </>
        )}
        {status === "finished" && (
          <FinishedSceen
            points={points}
            maxPossiblePoints={maxPossiblePoints}
            highscore={highscore}
            dispatch={dispatch}
          />
        )}
      </Main>
    </div>
  );
}

export default App;
